This episode is brought to you by Gnosis, building the open internet one block at a time.
Gnosis was founded in 2015 and it's grown from one of Ethereum's earliest projects
into a powerful ecosystem for open user-owned finance.
Gnosis is also the team behind products that had become core to my business and that of
so many others like Safe and CowSwap.
At the center is Gnosis Chain.
It's a low fee layer one with zero downtime in seven years and is secured by over 300,000
validators.
It's the foundation for real-world financial applications like Gnosis Pay and Circles.
All of this is governed by Gnosis Dow, a community-run organization where anyone with a GNO token
can vote on updates, fun new projects, and even run a validator from home.
So if you're building a Web3 or you're just curious about what financial freedom can look
like, start exploring at gnosis.io.
Welcome to Epicenter.
The show which talks about the technologies, projects, and people driving decentralization
and the blockchain revolution.
I'm Sebastian Cuccio and I'm here today with Ben Benjamin who's the founder of CAP and
CAP is a stablecoin protocol that has insured yield.
I know insurance can trigger some people, but we'll get into all of that and how the
protocol actually ensures it's deposits and how it generates yields.
We'll talk about the restaking component here, how it uses symbiotic to secure the
deposits and a whole bunch of other stuff.
Hey Benjamin, thanks for joining.
Thanks for having me, man.
Super excited about this.
So you're currently in China.
I'm curious just what's your impression of, yeah, what's your high level of impression
in China?
Is it the first time you've been there?
No, I've been to China many times.
I speak Chinese, so I come every year to practice Chinese actually.
And so this year I kind of combined my language practice with meeting some crypto people, but
yeah, I love China, it's a wonderful place.
Did you live there for a while?
I studied here for a year in Beijing during college, yeah.
And what's your sense of, because I think for a lot of people in the West, it's kind
of hard to put a finger on what Chinese life is like.
I recently listened to this Lex Readme episode, but this woman who was Chinese and sort of
like a Chinese economic and policy expert.
And she gave a really sort of like, she gave me sort of an eye-opening look on what life
in China is like, what people's aspirations are like, how people sort of deal with the
things that sort of in the West, we see as like state control and sort of bad, right?
But people actually thrive in these conditions, like, what's your sense of like, what life
is like in China and what are the biggest kind of misconceptions that people have about
China?
Yeah, I mean, I think there's like the people that have been to China and the people that
haven't.
And I love you that haven't have a very macro view of China.
So like politics, economics, world power, like struggles, right?
But I'm from a small country.
I'm from Chile.
From my point of view, China is the same as the US, right?
They remind me very much of the US, like big country type of culture with a lot of diversity,
obviously big economy, you know, I was just in the rural China last week or like early
this week, which is, you know, very different from Shanghai where I am right now.
But they're miles ahead of everywhere else, man.
Like all the cars are electric, super clean, it's very safe.
You know, the absorption of technology or the adoption of technology in everyday life,
I think it's higher, at least consumer technology compared to the West, especially Europe, right?
Like it's not even close, they don't use cash, they didn't use cards.
It's all like we chatter, Alipay.
So it's the digitalization of the countries, it's already there, it's been there for many
years.
Yeah, it's super impressive.
I think like that's probably one of the things that I've not been to mainland China, like
I'm in the Hong Kong, but like adoption of technology, I think like in Asia, it's just
like.
Oh, it's very different.
I think Hong Kong is like, it's amazing.
I love Hong Kong.
I like to start up with the Hong Kong, but mainland China, it's a different thing.
It's a different, completely different place, in my opinion.
From a living standard, obviously not from a political point of view.
Yeah, it's crazy how like, you know, being in Europe, and I don't want to make this all
about this, but it's just interesting to kind of get your perspective on this.
How like in recent years, there's been kind of a reversal in like rejection of technology
almost in Europe, and I wonder if that has to do with the fact that like a lot of technology
in Europe is owned and operated by US companies, if it's more of a kind of geopolitical rejection
than an actual technology rejection, but it is worrying to see like European people and
European kind of political discourse be like super anti-technology.
It's like, it's just so weird.
It's at least 40 years behind China, at least, like if you compare Berlin, oh my god, they're
used to use cash, you don't know what elevators are, like what's like all the ACs, not in most
places, and then you come to like Shanghai, I just shared an elevator ride with a robot,
you know, that was delivering something to me in the hotel.
So it's just like, you really can't compare, I mean love Germany, I actually came up with
the idea of cap in Berlin, but no man, it's just like crazy how different, and people
really don't think about that, because again, people's idea of China is very like a macro
about politics, about economics.
Cool, well, let's set that topic aside, but it's funny, like fighting Germany is fine.
Yeah, yeah, we'll use that as a hot take clip, but yeah, like we know you studied in Germany,
sorry, you studied in China, and you came up with the idea for cap in Germany, but what's
your journey, and how did you end up here, like how did you end up in a podcast talking
about your talking about your China journey and your founding of this company?
You know, life is crazy, right, who knew we would be here together talking about cryptocurrencies
in a podcast?
No, so I mean, I've been in crypto for quite some time, I started in the Hedera Hashcraft
space doing some infrastructure there, I started a stablecoin four or five years ago on Polygon,
so been in the stablecoin space for a while, and then obviously most recently, I started
a cap about a year ago, a little over a year ago, and yeah, that's kind of my little short
spiel about crypto.
What was the stablecoin project you were doing before?
Cheetahou, QIDEO, it was like very different, right, it's like at the height of the five
summer type of project, no fundraising, you know, max aloe to the community, air dropping
strangers, I don't even know who owns the token, like the largest whales, it's like
random people, but yeah, it was a wonderful project, it was the first cross-chain stablecoin.
Okay, and this is what I'm polygon.
Yeah, well, polygon started then Phantom, Avalanche, before you had OFT or ERXRC, we invented this
idea that the token when you bridge it from different chains should remain the same, it
should be fungible.
For us, that wasn't the case, right, you would have Wormhole, Avalanche, USDC, or, you know,
Layer Zero, Wormhole, Avalanche, USDC, Ethereum, like some long string like that.
And so you had some crazy pools on Solana, for example, with all the different versions.
So before the show, I was asking you about your hot take, and you said that you think
that stablecoins are less safe than what people think they are.
Can you expand on that?
Why should people be worried about their stablecoins?
I mean, I don't, I want to say you should be worried, but I do think you should be cautious
about, you know, where you put your money, because what happens every cycle is that,
you know, we learn certain lessons about, you know, what is safe and it's not safe.
But it's usually the people that get burned that actually retain the lessons, because if
you lose money, you really remember, you know, these kind of lessons.
If you don't lose money, or if you weren't there, then you don't know what to look for.
And so there are a few things that, you know, are kind of being done again in this cycle
that I'm worried about that have been done in the past, for example, over trusting third
party bridges, right, even though we have these token standards that's supposed to have
minting limits.
The minting limits are the size of the market capital of the tokens, right?
So there's like not really any like, you know, protections there.
When it comes to, you know, DeFi, we're, we're rebuilding Celsius and have, and all these
different, like, what's it called, like CD5 lending platforms that we're building them
on chain.
And they didn't suddenly become safe, right?
It's the same issue of unsecured lending to teams, but now we're doing it on chain.
And I think that's very unsafe and I'm worried about how that's going to end up.
So yeah, in general, I just think we should be very cautious about money because it's
money in the end of the day.
It's not a game and people can, you know, get hurt.
So you know, we used to talk about stablecoins in three buckets, or at least, you know, I
think like around 2021, people would talk about stablecoins as like there was the algorithmic,
you know, the likes of overall, you know, and then you had like sort of CDP, you know,
over collateralized and then, and then centralized, like USD C or something like that.
Do you think those categories still stand today and, or, or do you think that we're sort
of finding new types of stablecoins?
Yeah, I think that definitely one of those kind of died or it's like not very big anymore.
CDPs are not big anymore.
I think in general synthetic stablecoins, at least in number, they're not that big, right?
Like there's one big synthetic stablecoin right now that's extremely successful and
it's Athena, right?
Synthetic meaning is not fully backed by dollars.
It's partially backed by other things that are not dollars.
By and large, more stable, most stablecoins today are eventually redeemable for the dollar,
whether it be TBOs, etc.
So yeah, CDPs have definitely gone down in size.
Obviously, algorithmic ones are gone.
So really, now we find ourselves in, you know, world where there's two main buckets, I think,
where you have yield bearing stablecoins and there's many different kinds of yield bearing
stablecoins and you have these like non yield bearing stablecoins that are, you know, backed
by bank deposits and they're, you know, a genius at compliant like PYUSD, like USDC,
etc.
Why do you think the over collateralized model didn't work so well, right?
Because I mean, like, I think the starting principle of say something like MakerDAO was
to have a highly decentralized stablecoin with no kind of like, no USD collateral or
at least no reliance on centralized stablecoins as collateral.
And I think for people, a lot of people in crypto that got into crypto as a rejection
of the fiat system, that's like a very powerful idea, you know, today, like size, maybe, you
know, in the top five, but certainly a lot in the top two, which is dominated by USDC
and UST.
And then we have projects like FX, right, that claim to be super decentralized.
But, you know, I talked to them on last episode and it turns out that, you know, the dollar
peg is actually based on sort of relies on USDC.
Yeah, why do you think those like haven't really taken off and would you think they should?
Like, do you think there's a space for highly decentralized stablecoins that are over collateralized?
I mean, we have to acknowledge what the discourse is today in DeFi, right?
In the last cycle, it was decentralization, right?
How can we stay away from the traditional banking system?
And this is largely due to how regulators viewed crypto.
They did not want to engage with us, you know, they were going after teams.
And so you saw the rights of projects like liquidity, which is arguably the only decentralized
stablecoin, right, in crypto.
Now it's different.
What everybody cares about now, institutions, institutions, institutions, right?
How can we partner with banks?
How can we connect to the traditional finance system?
And these traffic guys don't want to play any games, right?
They don't want a stablecoin that's not backed by dollars, because that is risky.
Objectively is very risky, right, because we're not the US government.
We can't print dollars, and so this kind of push to be compliant or at least adjacent
to tradfi has pushed our whole industry to forget about decentralization and focus more
on scalability.
You think the industry is really forgetting about decentralization?
Yeah.
Yeah, I mean, yeah, I mean, I don't sound like a Debbie Downer, but like for real, I think
like people just don't, they don't value it as much as they care about scalability, right?
If you're looking at, you know, centralized L2s, if you're looking at every single stablecoin
that's coming out, right, is centralizing nature either because of their collateral or
because of the team's administrative power over, you know, the protocols, you know, we're
no longer counting how many multi-six signers there are on these multi-six.
We're no longer worrying about time logs, right, the idea of fully open sourcing your
code base is no longer the standard.
So just as like a review of where we are as an industry, it's just factual to say that
decentralization for D5 protocols in general is not at all at the top of mind.
Hmm.
Do you think that's a positive development and if that's the case, then why do we still,
why would we still call it D5?
Like, what is the distinction that like, I mean, is it just like, is it just FinTech
with better tech?
Is that like the direction we're going in or like, is there still some viability in
the D part of I?
Well, I think blockchain is not just decentralization, right?
There are many things about the blockchain that are good for finance.
Possibility is one that really comes to mind, right?
Like a lot of people talk about rebuilding Swift.
We already have it.
You know, literally any chain in the world with tokens can just, can be Swift, right?
It's just send and receive between wallets and there you go, it's done.
And so, you know, that's very powerful.
That's interesting.
I've never heard it.
I don't think it's negative.
I just think it's like, it's part of any industry, right?
You know, like right now AI probably is in a, like a moment of high, uh, romanticization
of what you can do with, with AI, whereas crypto, we've definitely gone through this
solution then.
And now we're looking at mass adoption.
And when you look at mass adoption, you have to get rid of the things that most people
don't care about.
You have to focus on the things that most people care about.
And for us, you know, boomers in crypto, that, you know, maybe we cared a lot about max decentralization
in the past.
You know, if we want the world to use crypto, maybe we need to think about what everybody
else cares about too.
What do you think is like, if there's one thing that the industry needs to kind of maintain
as a core principle, um, when interacting with the tradfi world or like traditional finance
kind of regulated world, like what is, what is the one property or the one thing that
like we can't deviate from in order to remain successful and like have a future where, you
know, this whole project has not been in vain.
Well, part of us maturing us in this sheet mean that means that we're no longer, um, sort
of unified in values.
We're definitely in a multipolar world, um, within crypto, where different groups have
different values, right?
Things that they think we should keep.
Personally, um, the group that I find myself in is, uh, that of safety.
I really think that, um, the transparency of smart contracts, the immutability of smart
contracts can provide a lot of safety, um, and if we can maintain that, um, then we can
make finance better than it is today.
I want to kind of come back to what you said earlier where decentralization is, uh, less
of a, is a value that is like sort of, um, not, not as coveted as it was perhaps previously,
right?
Or towards, um, we're moving away from, from the decentralized aspect of crypto.
Do you think that like, isn't, isn't it true that the infrastructure layers need to remain
decentralized?
Otherwise, they just kind of like, there's just databases, right?
And I like this entire project has been kind of useless.
We could have just built new data, we could just like done this on databases.
Is there some amount of value, right?
Like is it, is it like that maybe the higher layers of the stack are less decentralized?
Um, but the lower end of the stack are still like DeFi, I'm talking about like DeFi.
I'm talking about stable coins, right?
Stable coins DeFi people don't care about decentralization as much as they used to.
Um, for base layers, they do and, and the writing saw on the wall, who has the most stable
coins in crypto, it's Ethereum and nobody comes close, right?
We've seen so many people try to make their own stable coin chains for many years, there
have been many and they really haven't kicked off, right?
The L2s don't have a lot of stable coins at all.
And it's because at scale, money's not dumb, right?
At scale, people care about principal protection.
And so that's why they're on Ethereum, using the applications on Ethereum.
And some of those applications might be, you know, less central, decentralized that we
would want them to be.
But at least as you said, people care about the base infrastructure being decentralized.
Hmm.
Well, I think we'll come back to this maybe a little bit later, but, um, let's talk about
caps design.
And so, you know, broadly speaking, there's different participants within the protocol.
We have also sort of like different technical modules, different smart contract modules.
And, um, and cap utilizes restaking to ensure its deposits.
So give us a high level and maybe we can kind of drill down into the different parts.
Yeah.
So cap is a stable coin protocol to generate yield for users in a way that, um, we can
one, ensure the peg at all times and two, we can protect, um, users from the activities
that must be done to generate yield, right?
Uh, and the way that we do that is by two products.
One is CUSD, which is a digital dollar.
And this digital dollar you can mint it with others, stable coins, like USDC or money market
funds, like Benji and Biddle, um, what's great about that is one, you don't need liquidity,
right?
Cause at any point you can just redeem a hundred percent of the market cap, no slippage and,
and then you're good.
So you don't need to spend money on curve or, or any sort of, uh, AMMs, uh, which is quite
nice for us.
Um, and it also means for users, they can leave whenever they want, right?
They don't need to be worried about, uh, about the peg.
The other product that we build is, uh, you know, the staked version of it, which generates
yield and this yield comes from two sources, primarily at the beginning from the base yield
of each asset.
So for example, all the money market funds earned the US Treasury's yield, uh, and then
the stable coins, which are not allowed to share the yield because of Genius Act, um,
we use some, um, different strategy for each of them, depending on their circumstance.
For example, USDC, you would put it on Ave, um, because it's an over collateralized lending
market.
Uh, but that's, that's not the exciting part.
The exciting part is the other kind of source of yield.
Uh, and we've built this sort of allocation engine where third parties, uh, like regulated
financial institutions or DeFi protocols can compete with each other to generate yield
for our protocol.
And the way they do that is that they provisioned loans from our reserve, um, and pay some sort
of fee right in exchange for the loan, uh, and they go off and they all execute their
own strategy.
So there could be a thousand, 10,000 of these kind of yield generators competing at one
time to generate yield on the stable coin, um, but we don't trust any of them.
And so before they can come to our protocol and generate yield, they need to convince
a restaker on symbiotic or eigenlayer to vouch for them with their cryptocurrencies.
Um, and if the yield generator were to default and not pay back, we can slash whoever vouched
for them.
Yeah.
I'll stop there.
There's a lot you can go into.
But that's the high level.
Yeah.
It's, that's, that's great thing.
So, so there's two products.
There's the CUSD, which is the non-year yield bearing stable coin and then you have SDC
USD, uh, which, which generates yield, like why would someone hold CUSD over USDC?
What's, what's fundamentally the difference?
What's all about integrations, right?
In, in a lot of integrations in DeFi, like perp, Texas or, um, you know, pools, et cetera,
you can't use, uh, yield bearing assets.
You need a pegged asset.
And so, um, if you look at some of the larger, um, yield bearing stable coins today that have
a staking, uh, module, um, they all have lower than 70% staking rates.
And that's because of these integrations.
Yeah.
Okay.
That makes sense.
And so, like, so if we just kind of recap here, so the, the user deposits some, some
collateral.
And in this case, it's, it's a stable point.
So USDC or USDT, um, that goes into the protocol, um, and then you have the operators that
are hedge funds, um, primarily institutions that will use those, those coins to go and
generate yield.
So they're implementing their own strategy and some of those, some of those might be
implementing like super high risk strategies, others may be implementing like lower risk
strategies, but there's like a basket of strategies there.
And then we have restakers that are acting essentially as the backstop as the insurance
fund for, uh, against those USDCs, like against those deposits.
Insurance fund is a very passive term.
I would say there's sort of, uh, the decision makers.
So instead of having a Dow, say, you know, we're going to put our money here, we're going
to put our money there, restakers say, you know, Susquehana, you get to generate yield
for cap on $10 million or amber group you get to, you get to borrow $20 million to generate
yield.
And so they decide who gets to make yield, but in order to do that, they need to vouch
for them.
And so it's a bilateral relationship.
It's not like I as a restaker, I vouch for winter mute.
And now with amber group defaults, uh, I'm, I'm getting slashed.
I, I'm only exposed to whoever I vouch for.
And why is that important?
Because these, um, yield generators, what do they want to do?
It's not their money.
So they want to generate as much yield as possible so that their spread is very high.
Restakers, what do they want?
Well, they want yield, right?
Because, um, Bitcoin and ETH don't make yield compared to the dollars, not even close.
You know, the cryptocurrencies are not productive assets like the dollar.
And so they come to restaking land to get some sort of yield.
They don't want to get slashed above all else.
And so they're never going to underwrite extremely risky strategies or extremely risky, um,
third parties.
And so that kind of balances out the system.
So I don't know if you're familiar with this protocol.
I mean, it's, it's still like in the early phases of develop developments.
It's not released yet.
They have like a website, but, um, mezzanine where they have like kind of risk tranching.
Yeah, the tranching stuff.
Yeah.
I mean, there's, yeah, so it makes sense to have like risk tranching here.
So where, you know, you might have like low risk right where you're getting kind of like
the treasury yield and then maybe some higher risk and then like some very high risk.
And then that, all those different sort of yield sources are, um, are being combined
to provide the yield to the end user.
But there is some amount of like kind of backstop where the higher tranches are protecting the
lower tranches.
Yeah.
So here's the thing.
Retail has the mind to be making these decisions.
And so we abstracted away, um, you're right to say, you know, we have all these strategies,
but the dollar holders don't get any exposure to the risk, right?
If you're holding Stake CUSD, you are not exposed to the risk of the strategies.
Who is exposed is the restakers, right?
And so it doesn't really matter.
You don't have to tranch it.
Cause what would you tranch?
There's no risk to tranch, um, the tranching is on the other side where restakers can
choose like, Hey, I am super risk-averse.
I'm either fine.
So I'm only going to delegate to Bank of America, just to give you a random example.
Or maybe I'm risk taker XYZ and I want to get as much yield as possible.
Let me delegate to a crypto native market maker, right?
And so you'll, you'll have these different tranching on the other side and it's important
to keep it on the, you know, protocol or B to B side always tranching because, uh, there's
a lot of complexities, right, when either five delegates to, uh, institution, they're
not just trusting them, right?
They're signing some legal paperwork on the side to arrange what will happen if they get
sludge, et cetera, et cetera.
Who is in a good position to sue Bank of America, right?
It's not some, you know, uh, small farmer at all, right?
It's, um, these big projects that have raised millions of dollars.
They're in a good position to sue.
And so we're kind of shifting a lot of the burden of these, um, decisions and management
to the restakers, um, obviously not for nothing, right?
They get more yield than Ethan, Bitcoin have ever seen.
Okay.
Right.
So, so the restakers have legal agreements with the operators, the market makers, the
crypto, the crypto, private equity funds, et cetera.
Um, and those agreements lay out the types of strategies will have kind of like wrist
management, uh, provisions, et cetera.
And the restakers are on the hook for those operators doing their job right.
Exactly.
And the operators are on the hook to the restakers.
So you could put it like this, the stable coin holders are protected by smart contracts.
They don't need to trust anybody.
The restakers are protected by the law.
And so then, um, they should only delegate to good counterparties, right?
Uh, so scrijana may lose money sometimes.
Like everybody can lose money, but they are, are a good counterparty, right?
If they owe you money, they'll pay you back, right?
And so, um, that reduces the risk for the restakers.
So what, what constitutes the slashing event then and how are like, what's the flow of
capital for end users to be made whole if like one of the operators, you know, loses
all the money, you know, like, yeah, so we are a completely on chain platform.
Everything's smart contracts.
And so we don't really know if the borrower lost the money or not, right?
What do we know?
We know how much money they borrowed and we know how much money they've been delegated.
And so we track the collateral to debt ratio.
So how much delegated value is compared to the amount of loans and if that ratio falls
below a certain threshold, then that's when we liquidate sort of how over collateralized
lending markets track loads, like Avi and more full.
Right.
Okay.
So I guess one way to look at it would be that it's under collateralized lending where
the trenching happens between the operator and the restaker.
And it's kind of like abstracted away from the end user.
Sort of.
Yeah.
I mean, it's like, it's a three set of marketplace, which allows for, you know, three different
interpretations of the model, right, depending on where you're looking at it from.
From the point of view of the stable conholder, it's a miracle, right?
You're having an over collateralized lending market that's giving you three times the
rate of lava, right?
And you're like, what's what's going on, right?
And it's because you have this coincidence of once and needs of these three different
parties coming together.
Yeah.
I love a good cow coincidence of once.
Cool.
Okay.
So, and so who are the operators, like practically speaking, who are you working with and like,
what kind of strategies are they implementing?
I mean, if you, I guess like you don't know unless you're talking to them, which I suspect
you are.
Yeah.
We know, because they tell us things, which is nice.
So we launched a month ago.
And for the first two weeks, we focus purely on setting up the reserve, right, bootstrapping
it with USTC.
We got just over a hundred million in organic user deposits from in USTC.
And recently we started onboarding the restakers and the operators.
Now in terms of the operators, there's ample demand for liquidity.
Right now there's, there's a lot of market volatility.
There are a lot of opportunities to make yield.
And so demand for loans is pretty high.
We have operators like Amber Group or like GSR who are blue chip market makers in crypto.
We also have Susquehana, IMC and flow traders, which are their counter parties in the track
five world.
You know, these are huge enterprises over 200 billion in AUM.
So it's not just some random, you know, companies that we've put together.
And then finally, we also have some, um, define native names, right?
Like gauntlet soon to have RE7 as well.
So there's definitely a mix.
And that's the, that's the goal, right?
Because right now you have all these stable coins that are just making yields from treasuries
or maybe basis trade.
I can come to you and say, well, we're going to make yields from anything that the dollar
can touch because we can have a theoretically unlimited amount of operators to the extent
that restakers are willing to on the right, a theoretically unlimited amount of operators.
Okay.
So this is kind of like where that kind of like insured or covered loan, um, component
comes in where like the restakers are covering the loan.
We look at it as guarantees.
Right.
Okay.
Um, has there been a slashing event?
I mean, as you like, you launched a month ago, but, um, that's what I suspect now.
No.
And you know, we're, we're going through great pains to make sure that there's no slashing
events within at least the first year, um, because that would, that would be bad.
Right.
You know, people get spooked for all sorts of reasons in crypto.
Um, and so at the beginning, we are whitelisting who gets to borrow.
So even though the final say is actually at the restaker level, cap as a team is, can
can block certain people from borrowing, even if they have delegations.
And this is because the last thing we want is for somebody to start up a restaking protocol
and delegate to a meme coin trader and lose all their money and get slashed because then
all the other restakers are going to look really bad and their users are going to start
getting scared.
Like, or we next, even though, um, you know, a meme coin trader has nothing to do with
us.
It's completely different risk profile.
So which restaking protocols are you integrated with?
Right now every single major restaking protocol is either delegating or is in the process
of delegating to cap.
Some of them are faster than others.
We're very happy with, you know, Renzo as our first, uh, delegator on symbiotic and
concrete, the next one, but then sticks to an, a hyper rhythm, I've already delegated
this week as well.
So very happy with them, uh, and obviously excited to work with all the other ones that
are on the way.
Yeah.
I know you guys are working with symbiotic.
We're like, what's, what's unique about symbiotic that kind of like, um, makes this all work
as opposed to say, like other protocols, like, I can layer have to be political here.
Um, you know, they're both great projects with great teams.
And we are integrating both eventually right now.
We're in audit for, for I can layer, but we started with symbiotic, we actually finished
the coding fab and we've audited five times with like trail of bits, spear bit, um, recon
share like a bunch of, uh, top tier auditors.
Um, what do I like about symbiotic?
Well, it works.
Right.
All the, uh, all the kind of, uh, um, features that we needed are, we're live when we needed
them.
And so we were able to launch their, um, the team is very, um, you know, high quality.
They know how to ship.
And so everything kind of worked the way we wanted it to work.
Uh, and then finally obviously the modularity is actually pretty interesting, uh, because
obviously cap is not the original intended use of restaking, right?
It's not the original intended use case of, of, um, shared security as a whole.
Um, what could argue is one of the best, in my opinion, uh, but we can go into, uh, what
I think about shared security later.
Um, but yeah, that's, that's why I like symbiotic.
Yeah.
What, what do you think about shared security, like what are the really valid use cases for
shared security other than like this guarantee, this, this loan guarantee, which I agree.
I think it's like a really cool implementation and like, uh, use case for restaking.
Yeah.
I mean, I think it's, it's interesting that, you know, when I read eigen layers white paper,
I saw universal marketplace of trust, which I interpreted as, you know, you have people
with money, which is ETH, right?
And they have nothing to do with it because ETH doesn't have as many use cases as the
dollar.
And then you have people with skills, right?
And there's some sort of trust economy where the people with money can guarantee the actions
of the people with skills.
And then in practice, everybody was starting to build these POS, uh, like networks where,
um, they were just validating off chain data.
And I thought to myself, why are we limiting, um, this technology to just validating off
chain data?
If you think about it, validating data is not a very high margin business, right?
So can you really pay, um, the high cost of shared security just to validate data?
And the answer is no, right?
Right now these, um, validation systems are generating zero dollars in fee, not a cent,
not 10 cents.
They're generating zero.
And that's because, you know, you have to constantly validate a state, but you don't
constantly generate fees.
And the only way to make up for that, um, in balance in the accounting is to issue incentives.
And that's why Ethereum has inflation.
Sometimes that's why, you know, Bitcoin gives the token, right?
At the whole point of Eigen layer and symbiotic is that you don't need to have another token
and you just reuse the value of these tokens to have real value.
But if you, if you don't generate yield, then how do you pay?
Right?
Um, anyways, so I was not very happy with most folks focusing on validating data.
And I thought that we should really expand the use case of these guarantees to any sort
of activity.
It's just so happened that I'm using it to allocate funds of the stable coins collateral
to generate yield, but it really can be anything.
You know, earlier where we're talking about kind of like decentralization and, um, whether
or not, like, you know, it continues to be relevant, do you think that this particular
use case for restaking that is using a decentralized validator set and the, um, the assets that
gain value due to that decentralization to secure or act as kind of like on chain insurance,
do you think that that's a use case that can grow and kind of scale and become, you know,
the, the reasonable debts for, for restaking?
Cause like, I, I agree this whole like data validation, like doesn't seem like a really
good business long term.
Yeah.
I, I think guarantees in general, um, are definitely the way that restaking will survive
and will thrive.
Um, if you look at a lot of, um, you know, asset managers, both, both bracket banks,
um, one thing that they really like about crypto is obviously the composability.
The other part is smart contracts, right, because a big problem in tradFi is having
to trust other people trust is the biggest issue with finance.
And so smart contracts can alleviate that and organization systems like symbiotic can
alleviate that.
And so I think there's ample PMF for it.
Uh, and that's one, like the demand side on the supply side in terms of like ETH and,
and Bitcoin, these assets have a lot of value and I don't think we're paying taxes in Bitcoin
anytime soon.
And so there's not going to be a lot of use cases for Bitcoin compared to the dollar.
So this use case of restaking or using your assets to delegate to other people, I, I think
it will have a lot of PMF for a long time.
So we touched on this a little bit, but you mentioned the genius act, um, and, you know,
that some stablecoin projects were not like genius, I compliant and others probably won't
be.
Um, what do you think will be the dividing line there?
And, you know, for those projects that are genius, I compliant, um, is it mostly then just
kind of like having access to the US traditional financial system and maybe that's the dividing
line between what we consider to be kind of like the degen projects and those that are
not degen.
Um, yeah, what's your, what's your kind of like long term take on that?
Yeah.
I mean, I think we definitely live in a multipolar world outside of crypto as well.
So there's, is not the case that, you know, the US says this is what we need to do and
everybody does it.
Um, there will be folks that are not compliant and they're just maybe, you know, putting
their foundations in the payments and living in another country and, and kind of like just
not paying attention to American laws at all, you know, changing their UIs to block Americans.
So they can say, you know, we don't have to follow the laws.
Um, cap is our first round was with Susquehanna and our last round was Franklin Templeton to
great American institutions.
There's no hiding from US regulations, right?
We're also American.
And so the way we're going is the way of compliance, right?
And if regulators have a problem with us, we're, we're prepared to, um, to change things,
right?
And I think if you want to get big, if you want to be a large financial institution in
the future from the landscape of crypto, um, complying with American regulations is key
because that's where all of the world's money lives.
Yeah.
I agree.
I think like this change, this change in the administration, um, really has opened up
the gates for a lot of capital to come into the space.
And I think like a lot of people see it as like, Oh, like this legitimizes crypto in the
US, et cetera.
But the offshoot of that is that there's just like potentially hundreds of billions of dollars
that can flow into the ecosystem and, um, and that's not going to happen in probably
not in places like Europe, where the political discourse is very different.
Um, although I think there has been some, there has been some departure a little bit,
like at the E level from the CBDCs now that they've seen kind of like what the genius
act includes and what it can mean for US companies.
There is a little bit, at least I've, I've, I've kind of seen on Twitter as of some back
tracking, uh, to, to something that looks more like the US system.
Um, yeah.
What, what are your thoughts on the kind of like, yeah, you mentioned multi polarity.
Um, where do you think things go from here?
If we look at like, you know, the big polls, right?
So like US, Europe, BRICS and China.
Well, I'm not worried about Europe too much from a capital markets perspective.
Um, most of these large institutions that are involved in crypto within Europe are, uh, invested
in us.
So I'm see flow traders, edge capital, flow desk.
They're all, uh, not only investors in cap, but they're also operators, meaning they are
prepared to borrow and generate yield for a stablecoin protocol.
Uh, and so that's, that's all you need to see, right?
The, the people that need to be involved are involved and we'll have to see what regulators
do about that.
Um, obviously there's nothing to say about South America, right?
Because they're having fun.
They use crypto.
They don't care about, you know, the tokens, they, they've been using stablecoins for a
while and they're continuing to use stablecoins in the future, uh, because they're a wonderful
use case down there.
Um, our, our job is going to be to try to tap into as many of these regions as possible.
And the way that we're doing that is by accepting collateral assets that are integrated in each
area.
So, you know, America will have the stablecoins that are popular in America.
Uh, Europe will have, you know, the money market funds and the stablecoins are, uh, are
popular there.
Our job for CSV side, all of that is collateral.
So if you want to enter our yield system from Singapore, you can do that maybe through
UOB or if you want to enter our system from Germany, maybe you can do it via Deutsche
Bank's, you know, money market fund.
And so no matter where you are, capital will be able to connect, uh, via these kinds of
integrations with the money market funds and with the stablecoins.
Yeah.
I think my, my kind of high level view on the Europe, US situation, so that the US very
early, I mean, even like, I think US institutions, maybe, maybe the government, uh, like the
previous administration didn't see it this way, but at least like institutions saw crypto
and stablecoins as a, um, as like, a technology that could, uh, improve, uh, composability,
improve, um, reliability and, and, um, and security of the system as like something that
needed to be adopted by the industry with the administration kind of giving that a green
light.
And if it feels like it's, you know, full steam ahead, I think European banks and European
financial institutions, at least like the most more traditional ones, um, are more risk
averse.
And I think there's, um, there's like regulators and policymakers are kind of, um, sitting
in this really uncomfortable position where pushing stablecoins or the advancements of
stablecoins in Europe kind of undermines the power of traditional banks.
Um, and probably it will take a really long time for stablecoins to be kind of fully adopted
in Europe in the same way that it, you know, Europe was kind of behind the US in terms
of its adoption of e-commerce.
Any technology in Europe just takes a long time because institutions have so much political
power and at the same time, I mean, not that they don't have political power in the US,
but they're very risk averse.
They're very adverse to change.
They're very comfortable in their position, they're not pro-innovation.
I mean, all traditional industries are true, but I think, I think in Europe, there's an
even stronger sense of, uh, wanting to sort of like sit on your laurels and, uh, sit on
your established, uh, uh, rule, like position as an incumbent, which, um, kind of informs
policy.
Yeah.
I don't want to say too much about politics.
I, I might, our marketing, uh, person's going to be looking at, at this interview and, you
know, pulling their hair out.
So I, I wanted to maybe like, let's, let's just kind of do a thought experiment here
and, you know, let's kind of overlap stablecoins on the traditional finance system.
Um, so, you know, if, if we look at, if we look at, you know, kind of trad fire, right?
Like, let's, let's take a country like France, um, you know, the central bank, or at least
the European Central Bank, like issue zeros, flows down to the French Central Bank, the,
the French Central Bank, um, then lends those year, those euros out to, uh, lens out those
years out to, to, to banks, right, regulated banks and, um, and then those banks then like
issue their own kind of stablecoin, right?
Their own, uh, version of the euro, uh, to, to depositors, right?
To like their, their, um, uh, to their customers.
And you know, we have like, you don't, you don't see it as a, as a user of the system,
but in reality you have like a, you know, for Americans, these bank names are not going
to mean anything.
You have the banks, right, like that are issuing their own version of the euro, and that's
kind of abstracted away, um, but it works because you have this really good interoperability
between all of these systems because we have like kind of nationwide payment systems, and
then, and there's the backstop and it's underwritten by the central bank, which itself is underwritten
by like trust and institutions and their ability to lock people up, right?
Um, in crypto, it's a little bit more complicated because, um, we don't have this kind of like
institutional backstop and the interoperability is, is also there's, there's sort of complexity
in the interoperability aspect as well, where like, you know, your CUSD is not, um, as fluently
interoperable with any other stablecoin because the risks are kind of like different.
Do you, do you kind of like see this parallel as kind of being relevant and where, how do
we get to a point where anybody can just be using any stablecoin and they're, they're
not kind of encumbered by this, um, uh, this problem that like the different risk profiles
of the protocol introduces where these different coins are not interoperable.
Yeah.
I think it's a matter of, um, like the design of the mechanism, right?
Cap works with every single on ramper off, ramper, every single payment provider, you
know, every single bridge.
Why?
Because we're instantly redeemable for USDC, right?
And you can, within our reserve, you can sub within all the, the tokens, right, between
the money market funds, between the different stablecoins.
So, you know, you tell me there's an issue of interoperability, certainly not a cap,
right?
Because that's how we've designed the system.
And you'll see that happen, uh, with larger companies, like Coinbase, for example, you
know, they take PYUSD deposits, um, as USD, just like they take USDC.
And so it's just a matter of who trusts who cap trust, Franklin Templeton, and also they
trust BlackRock.
And so now we can act as like a bridge between them, uh, Coinbase trust circle and they trust
PayPal.
So now they can act as, uh, they can act as a bridge between them.
And so as, uh, as long as you kind of grow this pie of trust, you can start seeing this,
these connections.
And it's very similar to the banking system where overseas banks can connect to each
other via, you know, this wire system that we have, um, in, in TratFi with the added benefit
of, uh, of how elegant crypto is right for, uh, organizing token transfers, but it's not
a very difficult problem.
I, I just, I just think we need, if you have a good design, then interpretability is pretty
easy.
I want to like kind of zoom into this trust aspect.
And this kind of circles back to what we were talking about earlier.
Like, you know, a lot of people in crypto got into crypto because of kind of this rejection
of the fiat monetary system.
So if you talked early Bitcoiners and like early Ethereum folks, like this, this, this
idea that fiat, which actually, um, the etymology of that word kind of comes from the word trust,
right?
It's a monetary system where you, where you trust others.
Um, crypto kind of felt like it was a rejection of that.
I mean, it didn't feel like it was a rejection of that, um, of that, of that idea.
And you know, hearing you speak now, it sounds like you're talking like we're going back
into kind of a trust based system, um, but with one kind of one, uh, distinction is that
because risk is now kind of spread across different, uh, restakers, uh, different,
uh, kind of funds, et cetera, in the case of cap, it creates a, a more opaque central kind
of like, authority to who is responsible, right?
So it actually makes things more complicated for the end user, uh, who has like suffered
some damages because of misconduct, right?
Well, it depends on how you do it.
Like, for example, like with us, you know, we take Benji, we take UCC as collateral and
you can track and see, you know, these are the collaterals we take.
It gets more complicated if, you know, you're, uh, backed by Eve, but then you also put money
in Ave.
And then who knows where I have is putting that money and, and you have like these more complicated
systems.
And there are such stable coins where you don't really know where the money's being put.
And so I agree with you that the, the question of, okay, I lost money, who, who's fault wasn't,
will become more complicated when you have these stable coins that are kind of acting
like hedge funds and putting their money in all sorts of places.
But it's certainly not the case of cap, because we're all DeFi PTSD, you know, survivors.
And we've built cap in a way that you're able to track what you've just described, right?
Who, who is responsible for maintaining the quality of the collateral?
I guess it's not a reflection on cap, but just kind of like as the, uh, for the industry
as a whole.
So where the risk is more spread, perhaps it means that the chances of something happening
that, yeah, the chance of something happening is, is reduced, but, you know, it's increased,
but it's like the, the, the penalty of it happening is lower.
Sorry.
The penalty, the penalty may be less, right?
Um, but also like the crypto world operates in a space where, you know, there is a lot
of opacity around like where operators are situated and certainly like, I think regulation
can kind of kind of help with that where, you know, there may be like clear, um, pass
to litigation when that happens, but yeah, I mean, look at what happened to multi-chain
the bridge.
They got hacked by the Chinese government or like a local government and all the money
got stolen.
So finance, froset, circle, froset, telefroset, they haven't returned the penny to users.
And the Phantom Foundation has been suing Binance and all these teams to give the money back
and they've refused to do it.
And, and they haven't been able to get the money back because, you know, that's just how
regulations are.
Um, and so you're, you're right.
Um, I see, and that's kind of why we built cap the way we built it because I really just
don't think that users are in a place to get any sort of recourse.
If your favorite yield bearings, they will coin at the pegs, you're going to be suing
some random Cayman entity, right with, um, you know, a director who is the same director
for every other, uh, Cayman entity in crypto and you're going to find yourself without
a nickel of recourse.
Yeah, I think, I think this is where like regulation will play a huge role is where these
entities need to be kind of like local in their jurisdictions where they're situated
and where, um, they become highly sort of entangled with the traditional finance system, central
banks, et cetera.
Uh, but I think we're like really long way until that happens.
Yeah, that's why you have to choose like, do you want to trust the government or do you
want to start, trust more contracts?
And I think any project that's in the middle where you're not trusting smart contracts,
you're not trusting the government, you actually trust is some random developer team.
I am very scared of those projects because I know I can trust the government somehow
a little bit.
And I know I can definitely trust more contracts.
I know darn well, I can't trust random developer teams.
Yeah.
Well, some, some, some people would definitely not agree with you that you can trust the
government a little bit, but that's a conversation for another trust like regulators more than
I trust a random, you know, startup in general.
Yeah.
I think some people might that agree with that.
But yeah, obviously.
Where the kind of proliferation of stable coins does excel is offering these different
trust assumptions.
So you have like stable coins that are fully centralized where you don't have to trust
anyone.
And then you have stable coins that are fully centralized and you have like sort of things
in between where you're relying on centralized stable coin deposits, but those deposits are
backed by a decentralized asset in the case of cap, right?
So like you're, you're backing the, you're backing the centralized stable coin deposit
in the form of USDC USDT with an insurance or a guarantee that is secured by a decentralized
asset.
And that might be like the, the middle ground that we need to scale, but then also remain
decentralized.
How could I disagree with such a beautiful explanation?
Well, Benjamin, thanks for coming on.
Anything you want to share before we wrap up?
I would say that, you know, a lot of people have said recently that the stable coin space
is extremely crowded and there are too many stable coins, but I think they're wrong.
I think they're not that many stable coins that are differentiated in crypto.
And so if you are, you know, a founder that's trying to make a new stable coin, make it,
you know, I want there to be a hundred new stable coins, a thousand new stable coins because
the more innovation that happens, the more liquidity we're going to get on chain.
And that will benefit everybody because it's much easier to convince somebody that's using
another stable continuous yours than it is for you to convince somebody that has money
like Bank of America to use your stable coin.
And so yeah, I just, I will have a call to, you know, not be discouraged by, you know,
how many stable coins there are in crypto.
Cool.
Well, thanks for coming on.
Enjoy the rest of your time in China and good luck with this.
- Thank you.